(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-28T01:27:26.479015",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
皆様、本日は
Ladies and gentlemen, today...
綺々羅ヴィヴィ生誕祭2026にお越しくださいまして
...thank you very much for coming to Kiki Vivi Birthday Celebration 2026.
誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you so very much!
開演に先立ちまして
Prior to the start of the performance,
皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
I would like to make a few requests and announcements.
本配信は一部収録もございますが
Although parts of this stream are pre-recorded,
生配信部分もございますので
there are live portions as well!
いっぱいコメントやポストをして
So please send lots of comments and posts
たくさん盛り上げてください！
and make it super exciting!
みんな、コメントも見えてるよ！
Everyone, I can see your comments!
本配信のハッシュタグは
The hashtag for this stream is...
「#ヴィヴィ生誕祭2026」です！
...#ViviBirthdayLive2026!
ライブの感想など
Please post your thoughts on the live show
SNSでたくさんポストしてください！
on social media using the hashtag!
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどによる
Taking photos during the show using cameras or smartphones
写真撮影は、大歓迎です！
is highly welcomed!
たくさんポストして盛り上げていただきましたら
If you share lots of photos and build up the hype,
めっちゃ嬉しいです！
I'd be super-duper happy!
それでは、開演まで
Well then, please wait just a little longer
今しばらくお待ちください！
until the show begins!
皆様！
Everyone!
本日は、氷川ビビ 生誕祭2026に お越しくださいまして、
Thank you very much for coming to the Hikawa Bibi Birthday Festival 2026 today.
誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
開演に先立ちまして、皆様にお願いとご案内を申し上げます。
Before we begin, we would like to present some requests and reminders.
本配信は、一部収録もございますが、生配信部分もございますので、
Although parts of this stream are pre-recorded, there are also live portions,
いっぱいコメントやポストをして、たくさん盛り上げてください！
so please leave lots of comments and posts, and keep the excitement going!
コメントも全部見えてるよ！
I can see all of your comments!
本配信のハッシュタグは「ビビ生誕祭2026」です。
The hashtag for today's stream is #BibiBirthdayFestival2026.
ライブの感想など、SNSで、めっちゃたくさんポストしてください！
Please post a ton of your thoughts about the live show on SNS!
開演中、カメラやスマートフォンなどによる写真撮影は、
During the show, taking photos with cameras or smartphones is...
大歓迎です！
...highly encouraged!
たくさんポストして盛り上げてくださるとビビ、大歓喜です！
Bibi will be absolutely thrilled if you post lots of them and hype things up!
皆さん！ビビと楽しむ準備、できてますかー！
Everyone! Are you ready to have fun with Bibi?!
おーい！ビビめっちゃ緊張してるよ！みんな震えるビビの膝を、ポストで支えてくれ！ビビ、口も回らんようになってきた！
Hey! Bibi is super nervous! Everyone, support my trembling knees with your posts! I'm getting all tongue-tied!
でも！ビビにメロメロになる準備、できてますかー！
But still! Are you ready to fall head over heels for Bibi?!
あ、あそこみんなもう、でも、すでにビビにメロメロか！
Ah, actually, is everyone already head over heels for me?
今日は、アイドル全開のビビを目に焼き付けてな！
Today, make sure to burn the sight of Bibi in full-on idol mode into your eyes!
たくさん、可愛いって言って！
Say "You're cute" a whole bunch!
可愛い？
Am I cute?
知ってる！
I know!
それでは、開演まで今しばらくお待ちください！
Well then, please wait a little longer until the show starts!
うーん、なんだろな。もう、本当にこの私がいるのに、
Hmm, what is it? Honestly, even though I'm right here...
誰よりも君のことを思っている人が、こんなにも近くにいるんだけどな。
someone who thinks of you more than anyone else is right this close to you.
よし、こうとなったら、そろりそろりと参ります。
Alright, since it's come to this, I'm going to take it step by step.
シュビドゥビ、アーユーレディ？ゴー！
Shooby-dooby, are you ready? Go!
カウントダウンラブ
[Song: Countdown Love]
ねえ このあと 予定とかあるの？
Hey, do you have plans after this?
帰り道も 一緒だし どう？
We're going the same way home, so how about it?
そういえば今日 髪の分け目 変えたんだよ 気づいて
By the way, I parted my hair differently today... notice it!
あーもう！アルバイト代何に使ったって、あんまり実感ないなぁ、どうなんだろうこれ？
Ah, geez! I don't really feel like I spent my part-time job money on anything, what's up with that?
そうだ、おみくじ、凶なんだよな。だなんて、
Oh right, my fortune was "bad luck." But then again...
ナナナ、どうなのかな、私の方なんじゃないのかな
na-na-na, how about it? Isn't it actually my turn?
えーい、知らない！
Geez, I don't know!
周りに目移りしないでよ
Don't let your eyes wander to others,
私だけを I want you
I only want you to look at me, I want you!
なんか少しでも一緒にいたいんだけど
I want to be with you even for just a little bit...
I need you ねえねえ、そろそろ気づいちゃってるんじゃない？
I need you! Hey, hey, haven't you noticed by now?
さあ、ギュンとして
Come on, squeeze me tight...
ねえ、もう、こっち向いて<
...hey, look over here!
ちゃっちゃっと高鳴るテンポで
In a fast, pounding tempo,
だんだん絡み合っていくベース
the bass gradually intertwines.
バババ 撃ち抜かれるエールを
Bang, bang, bang! The cheer shoots through...
ドキドキ、ハートがテンパしている
Pounding, my heart is panicking.
もう、いっそのこと君と永遠に
Now, I'd rather be with you forever...
エンドレス、ラブアゲイン
...in an endless love again!
ときめき、高鳴る、ほら、目を合わせてよ
Thump-thumbing, pounding, look, look into my eyes!
ゆびさき なぞって 教えてあげる
Tracing with your fingertips, I'll let you know...
恋に気づくまでのカウントダウン
...the countdown until you realize it's love!
目と目合わせて クラクラり
Eyes meeting, feeling dizzy...
いつでも準備はできてる
...I'm always ready!
私だけ見ててね
Only look at me, okay?
絶対！
Promise!
イェーイ！
Yay!
朝の占いで1位だから決まるモチベーション
Being first in the morning horoscope decides my motivation.
視覚 聴覚 言語の3つで人の印象は決定します
By vision, hearing, and words, a person's impression is decided.
甘口言葉のチョイス 今日も可愛いでしょ？
My choice of sweet words, I'm cute today too, right?
Hey Hey, Hurry up! Show time! さあ君だけのワンタイム
Hey Hey, Hurry up! Show time! Now, a one-time just for you!
アイ！ 一期一会に感謝 友情感じる エナジー！
Love! Appreciating once-in-a-lifetime encounters, feeling friendship... Energy!
ご褒美を頂戴 私が可愛いから しれっとご褒美
Give me a reward, because I'm cute, a sneaky reward!
だけど恋はあんまり実感ないな
But I don't really have a sense of what love is.
どうなんだろう これけど実際問題 振り向いてくれたら
How is it really? But as a practical matter, if you turn to look at me...
痛い痛いほど問題ない！
No problem, even if it hurts!
また不器用なんだから 少しは素直になって
You're being clumsy again, so be a little more honest.
ねえ これじゃない気がする
Hey, I feel like this isn't it!
One, Two, 極上席 最前から見ててほしいな
One, Two, I want you to watch from the very front row's best seat.
Three, Four, ねえねえ ぼちぼち分かっちゃってるんじゃない？
Three, Four, hey, hey, haven't you figured it out by now?
さあ キュンとしてね
Now, make your heart flutter!
もう、こっち来てよ！
Geez, come over here!
ちょちょ ちょっとカウント君にピピピ 恋感が駆け引きの連鎖
W-W-Wait, countdown beep-beep-beep to you, love feelings are a chain of tactics,
ただ気づくべき距離感 続いて
just notice this distance, and continuous...
ドキドキハートがテンパしている
My thumping heart is panicking
もういっそのこと私永遠に
I might as well be yours forever
ハピネス ラブ & ピース 愛の言葉で示すアイ
Happiness, love & peace, showing my love with loving words
あっぷあっぷしちゃって ほらまた眠れないよ
Struggling to breathe, look, I can't sleep again
指折り数えて教えてあげる
Counting on my fingers, I'll let you know
恋に気づくまでのカウントダウン
The countdown until you realize it's love.
うそだなぁ、どう考えてもツンデレって言葉が合うのかなぁ
No way, no matter how I think about it, does the word "tsundere" suit me?
恋愛の無神経主人公かと思いますよねぇ
Don't you think you're like an insensitive romance protagonist?
もう我慢ならない！分かりやすく参ります！
I can't take it anymore! I'm going to make it obvious!
Shubidu, Are you ready? Go!
イェーイ！ はい はい！
Yay! Yes, yes!
うわうわうわうわ
Uwa uwa uwa uwa
はい はい！
Yes, yes!
うーーー
Uuuu...
ちょっと強がりで 照れくさくて
A bit of a bluff, and a bit embarrassing,
でも止まらないの
but it just won't stop.
いつかを待ち続けたいよ
I want to keep waiting for that day,
私を見ててね
so keep looking at me, okay?
好き
I love you.
エンドレス ラブ & ピース 感情のパーティー満たすアイ
Endless love & peace, love filling the party of emotions
1, 2, レディスタート ほら目を合わせてよ
One, Two, ready start, look, make eye contact
指先なぞって教えてあげる
Tracing with my fingertips, I'll let you know
恋と気づくまでをカウントダウン！バン！
Countdown until you realize it's love! Bang!
目と目合わせてクラクラり
Making eye contact, getting dizzy,
いつでも準備はできてる
I'm always ready.
触れ合えばもうクラクラり
If we touch, I get dizzy,
今すぐ抱きしめて
hold me right now.
私だけ見ててね、絶対！
Only look at me, promise!
イェーイ！ はい はい！
Yay! Yes, yes!
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ 今日はどこに行こうかな
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where should we go today?
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ 二人の思い出を重ねて
Hey, hey, hey, hey, let's build up our memories together.
眩しくて 目が覚めた日は
On the day I woke up to the dazzling light,
ちょっとだけ 気持ちいい
it felt just a little bit good.
眠いけど せっかくだし
I'm sleepy, but since we have the chance,
キミはもう 起きているかな？
are you already awake?
今日の予定を 勝手にたてるの
I'll decide our plans for today on my own.
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ 今日はどこに行こうかな
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where should we go today?
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ 二人の思い出を重ねて
Hey, hey, hey, hey, let's build up our memories together.
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ 明日はどこに行こうかな
Hey, hey, hey, hey, where should we go tomorrow?
キミといると 行き先はどこも 特別な場所に変わるの
Wherever we go, being with you turns it into a special place.
信号が 青に変われば
If the traffic light changes to green,
あとは この先に待ってるのは
what's waiting for us beyond this point is
広い海
the vast ocean.
海岸を
The coast,
そう 野に駆ける
yes, running through the fields,
いつもの音楽をBGMにして
with our usual music playing as BGM.
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
今日はどこに行こうかな
Where should we go today?
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
二人の思い出を重ねて
Let's make more memories together.
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
明日はどこに行こうかな
Where should we go tomorrow?
キミといると いう奇跡は
The miracle of being with you
どこもかしこもカラフルに変わるの
turns everything around us colorful.
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
今日はどこに行こうかな
Where should we go today?
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
二人の思い出を重ねて
Let's make more memories together.
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
明日はどこに行こうかな
Where should we go tomorrow?
キミといると いう奇跡は
The miracle of being with you
どこもかしこもカラフルに変わるの
turns everything around us colorful.
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
へへっ
Hehe!
IRIS OUT
ダメ ダメ ダメ 脳みその中から
No, no, no, from inside my brain...
やめろ馬鹿とわめくモラリティ
morality screams, "Stop it, you fool!"
だりー べりー たりー
Darly, Very, Tarly...
半端なく love ときらめき
Extreme love and sparkle,
浮き足立つフィロソフィー
a restless philosophy.
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣いか
An upturned glance that is deadly cute,
何が地雷に触れるくらい
almost touching some landmine.
ばらまく嵐 気付けば惨事
Scattering storms, and before we know it, a disaster.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
You are the one at fault for being born in this world.
やたらと しんどい
Extremely exhausting
恋わずらい
is love sickness.
バラバラになる 頭とこの身体
My head and body are falling apart,
けど 目からアイラブユーが吹き出て
but "I love you" bursts from my eyes...
アイリスアウト
Iris Out!
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
あばらの奥のざらめが溶けて
The brown sugar deep in my chest melts,
きらりになりそう
and is about to sparkle.
どこ？ バックライト
Where? The backlight...
ぼやけた瞳にさ
into my blurry eyes.
いま この世で君だけ大正解
Right now in this world, you're the only correct answer.
だりー だりー
Darly, Darly...
ひっくり返っても勝ち目ない
Even if turned upside down, there's no chance of winning.
君だけのルールは適用外
Rules meant only for you do not apply.
オセロは黒しかない 勝ち上げ放題
Othello is nothing but black, an infinite winning streak.
君が笑顔で放った 刃だけダブらせて
The blade you released with a smile, I only let it overlap,
これっぽっちのスティグマ 申し訳ねぇな
a mere stigma like this, my deepest apologies.
つん 指をさして
Pointing a finger...
つん 貫いて
piercing through...
つん ここ弱点
here's my weak point!
死ぬほど可愛い 上目遣いか
An upturned glance that is deadly cute,
何が地雷に触れるくらい
almost touching some landmine.
ばらまく嵐 気付けば惨事
Scattering storms, and before we know it, a disaster.
この世に生まれた君が悪い
You are the one at fault for being born in this world.
パチモノでもいい なんでもいい
Even a knock-off is fine, anything is fine.
いま君とうなずいてる 全て欲しい
Right now, I'm nodding with you, I want everything.
けど 目からアイラブユーが吹き出て
But "I love you" bursts from my eyes...
アイリスアウト
Iris Out!
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do? What should I do with these feelings?
あばらの奥のざらめが溶けて
The brown sugar deep in my chest melts,
きらりになりそう
and is about to sparkle.
どこ？ バックライト
Where? The backlight...
ぼやけた瞳にさ
into my blurry eyes.
いま この世で君だけ大正解
Right now in this world, you're the only correct answer.
だりー だりー
Darly, Darly...
イェー！
Yeah!
はーい！みんなー！
Hi, everyone!
挨拶します。せーの、
Let's do our greeting. Ready, set...
うーーん、ビビ！
Uuun... Bibi!
いつもはキラキラなキキララビビですわー！
It's your always sparkling Kikirara Bibi!
みんなー！
Everyone!
ここまで3曲続けて披露させていただきましたー！
I just performed three songs in a row for you!
『カウントダウンラブ』ね、『アイリスハート』
They were "Countdown Love" and "Iris Heart".
それぞれビビどうやった？
How did you like Bibi in each of them?
可愛くて、セクシーで、ヘルシーやった？
Was I cute, sexy, and healthy?
はい！まあね、見たら分かるヘルシーセクシーキュートのビビなんですけども、
Yes! Well, as you can see, I'm the healthy, sexy, and cute Bibi, but...
あ！そして！みんなー！
Oh! And, everyone!
今情報が入りました！トレンド2位だってー！
I just got some news! We are trending at #2!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you so much, everyone!
でもでも、ビビ1位になりたいの！1位になりたいなー！
But Bibi wants to reach #1! I want to be #1!
ぜひですね、今日のハッシュタグは、
So please use today's hashtag...
「ビビ生誕祭2026」で、もうめちゃめちゃたくさんポストしまくってください！
...#BibiBirthday2026 to make tons of posts!
可愛いビビをいっぱいスクショしてな！
Take lots of screenshots of cute Bibi, okay?
はい！そして今回のですね、ライブのコンセプトは、
Yes! And the concept of today's live concert...
まあ先ほども言ったように、キュート、ヘルシー、セクシーの3つになってます！
...is Cute, Healthy, and Sexy, as I mentioned earlier!
はい、雰囲気もね、テーマに合わせて、まあ、変わってたんですけど、
And the atmosphere has been changing to match the theme...
この舞台、みんな気づいたかな？
...did everyone notice the stage?
はい、この後ね、楽曲もテーマによって変化していくのでお楽しみに！
The upcoming songs will also change based on the theme, so look forward to it!
あ、こんなデカいステージに立ててビビ幸せ者やー！
Ah, I'm so happy to be standing on such a huge stage!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
それでは、次はゲストパートです！
Now, up next is the guest part!
ゲストパートは収録なのですが、
The guest part is pre-recorded, but...
あんなことやこんなことも、しちゃいますよ！
...I'll be doing this, that, and all kinds of things!
もう、いやらしい！
Oh my, how naughty!
Cry Baby / 作詞・作曲: 藤原聡
[Song: Cry Baby / Lyrics & Composition: Satoshi Fujihara] Confirmed Visual Event.
胸ぐらをつかまれて強烈なパンチを
Grabbed by the collar, taking an intense punch,
食らってよろけて 肩を並べうずくまった
I staggered and crouched down shoulder-to-shoulder with you.
予報通りの雨にお前はにやけて
You grinned at the expected rain,
「傷口が綺麗になる」なんて嘘をつく
telling me a lie: "The rain cleanses our wounds."
いつも口喧嘩さえ
Usually, you can't even argue well,
うまく出来ないくせして
but you still make
冴えない冗談言うなよ
such dull jokes.
あまりのつまらなさに目が潤んだ
My eyes welled up at how boring they were.
何度も青あざだらけで涙を
Covered in bruises over and over again,
流して 流して
shedding tears, shedding tears,
不安定な心を肩に預け合いながら
we lean our unstable hearts on each other's shoulders,
腐りきったバッドエンドに抗う
fighting against a rotten bad ending.
なぜだろう 喜びよりも心地よい
For some reason, the pain is more pleasant
痛みがずっしりと響いて
than the joy, echoing deep inside.
濡れた服に舌打ちしながら
Tsking at our wet clothes,
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
we look at each other's swollen faces and laugh
どしゃぶりの夜に
on the night of the downpour...
誓ったリベンジ
vowing our revenge.
胸ぐらをつかみ返して
I grab you back by the collar,
反撃のパンチを
to throw a counter-punch—
繰り出すくらいじゃなきゃ お前の隣には立てないから
if I can't do at least that, I can't stand by your side.
相手がなんだあれひるまない
No matter who the opponent is, I won't flinch.
何度もされても諦めない
No matter how many times I'm beaten, I won't give up.
忘れるな忘れるなと言い聞かせ続けた思い
The feelings I kept telling myself never to forget, never to forget...
やり直して しくじって やり過ごして 離れたいね
Redoing it, messing up, getting through it, wanting to leave...
やり直して しくじって やり過ごして 肩を貸して
Redoing it, messing up, getting through it, lend me a shoulder...
あぁ 傘はいらないから
Ah, I don't need an umbrella,
言葉をひとつくれないか
so won't you give me a single word?
ぬるい優しさではなく
Not some lukewarm kindness,
弱音に侵された 胸の奥を
but words that cut deep into my heart,
抉るような言葉を
invaded by a sense of weakness.
何度も青あざだらけで涙を
Covered in bruises over and over again, shedding tears...
流して 流して
Shedding them, shedding them,
汚れた心を肩に預け合いながら
while leaning our dirty hearts on each other's shoulders,
腐りきったバッドエンドに抗う
we struggle against this rotten bad ending.
なぜだろう 喜びよりも心地よい
Why is it that, more than joy, this comfortable
痛み ずっしりと響いて
pain resonates heavily within us?
濡れた服に舌打ちしながら
Clicking our tongues at our wet clothes,
腫れ上がった顔見合って笑う
we look at each other's swollen faces and laugh,
土砂降りの夜に
in this downpouring night.
囚われの日々に
In these captive days,
問いかけるように
as if asking a question,
光った瞳の中で
inside those shining eyes,
誓ったリベンジ
is the revenge we swore.
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Can I take a bite?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて 悪い子だね
Saying "I can't go on anymore", what a bad kid.
試したいな
I want to test you,
いっぱいで吐き出したい
I want to fill up and let it all out.
まだ絶対いけるよ
I know you can still keep going!
最低最高 ずっと行き来してる
I've been going back and forth between the worst and the best.
甘くなる不安の果実
The fruit of anxiety grows sweet.
No, more, 果てるまで息をしても
No, more, even if I breathe until the end,
要られないだけ 煩いだけ
I'm just unneeded, just annoying.
誰かと居れば それはたられば
If I'm with someone, it's all "what-ifs,"
強がってたって気持ちにゃ逆らえない
even if I act tough, I can't go against my feelings.
離れていても 感じてるエモ
Even if we're apart, I can feel the emotion,
繋がって確かめてたら 死ぬかも
if we connect to make sure, I might die.
いいもん 悲しいもん
It's fine, it's sad,
切ないもん
it's painful,
君のすべてを喰らうまで
until I consume all of you,
絶叫
scream!
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Can I take a bite?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて 悪い子だね
Saying "I can't go on anymore", what a bad kid.
試したいな
I want to test you,
いっぱいで吐き出したい
I want to fill up and let it all out.
まだ絶対いけるよ
I know you can still keep going!
あたし
I'm a...
求めちゃってまた枯らしちゃって ほら嫌な感じ
Demanding it, then letting it wither again, see, what an unpleasant feeling.
泣いて忘れて はじめまして
Crying, forgetting, and saying "nice to meet you."
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
愛情をください まだ絶対いけるよ
Please offer me your condolences, I know we can still keep going!
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
まずはこっちおいで
First, come over here.
内緒の想い 洗いざらい
Exposing all of my secret feelings,
吐き出したなら 惑わせばかり
if I let them out, it's nothing but confusion.
割り切れないけど 余りじゃない
I can't divide it evenly, but it's not a leftover.
そっと朝まで 通せんぼ
Gently blocking your path until morning.
繰り返すヤダ
Repeating "no,"
わがままはもっとヤダ
selfishness is even worse.
欲張ってまたチャンスを逃すのだ
Being greedy and letting the chance slip away again.
予報もあいまいも 構えたいけど
The forecast is ambiguous, and though I want to prepare,
重ねて押しつぶされちゃうのかも
they might pile up and crush me.
いいもん 悲しいもん
It's fine, it's sad,
切ないもん
it's painful,
君のすべてを喰らうまで
until I consume all of you.
いいじゃん 楽しいじゃん
It's fine, it's fun,
気持ちいいじゃん
it feels good,
溺れるまでがくせになるね
drowning in it becomes a habit, doesn't it?
絶叫
Scream!
あたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire.
いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Can I take a bite?
「もう無理もう無理」なんて 悪い子だね
Saying "I can't go on anymore", what a bad kid.
試したいな
I want to test you,
いっぱいで吐き出したい
I want to fill up and let it all out.
まだ絶対いけるよ
I know you can still keep going!
君もヴァンパイア
You're a vampire too.
いいの？吸っちゃっていいの？
Is it okay? Can I take a bite?
「もう無理もう無理」だっていわせて欲しい
I want to make you say "I can't go on anymore."
君がいなきゃ絶対にいけない
Without you, I absolutely can't make it,
ほら絶賛させてよ
come on, let me receive high praise!
求めちゃってまた枯らしちゃって 今何回目？
Demanding it, then letting it wither again, what time is it now?
星が見えるような泡の中で
In the bubbles where stars seem visible.
延長をください まだ絶対いけるよ
Please give me an extension, I know we can still keep going!
君もヴァンパイア
You're a vampire too.
まずはこっちおいで
First, come over here.
絶対いけるよ
We can definitely keep going!
ねえ あたし知ってるよ 君がひとり
Hey, I know that you are all on your own.
知ってるの？ 知ってるよ
Do you know? Yes, I know.
びくんびくん震えてさ
Twitching and trembling,
声もダダ漏れなんだわ
even your whimpers are completely leaking out.
正直に言っちゃえよ
Just speak honestly,
バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ
your cover is blown, so just say it.
聞いてんの？
Are you listening?
ふつふつ恥ずかしい
You're getting all embarrassed,
みんな隠しているだけ
but everyone is just hiding it.
むふっ
Hehe.
ねえ あたし知ってるよ
Hey, I know...
ねえ私知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君がひとり涙流してるの知ってるよ
I know you're shedding tears all alone.
ぐすんぐすん凹んでた
Sniffling and feeling down...
弱い人からいいんじゃない
Isn't it fine to start with the weak ones?
朝が来るまで一緒越そう
Let's get through this together until morning.
もっと泣いたって何遍だって受けとめてあげる
No matter how much you cry, I'll accept it every time.
もう我慢しないでいっぱい吐きだしてね
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out.
おねがい 君が欲しいの 慰めさせて
Please, I want you, let me comfort you.
shake shake 愛の才能で
Shake, shake, with the talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away.
濡れていたいね いいでしょ
I want to be wet, is that okay?
なめとって 飲みほしたい だ、だ、だ、だってば保存
I want to lick it up and drink it dry, because...
おねがい君が欲しいの 手探り散らして保存
Please, I want you, groping around.
shake shake ナッツのサイズで
Shake, shake, in the size of a nut.
わけてくれなきゃ 君じゃない
If you don't share it, you're not yourself.
感じてたいね いいでしょ
I want to feel it, is that okay?
吸いとって 救いたい だ、だ、だ、だってば
I want to suck it up and save you, because...
君の中
Inside of you...
ねえ私知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君がひとり悔しがってるの知ってるよ
I know you're feeling frustrated all alone.
ずくんずくん高鳴るじゃん 君はオスであることをやめない
My heart is throbbing, you won't stop being a male.
ねえ私知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君はできる子 知ってるよ
I know you're a capable person.
つらい時は弱いくらいでちょうどいい
When times are tough, being a little weak is just right.
私それでも好きだよ
But I still love you anyway.
おねがい 君が欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ
Please, I want you, call my name.
いっせーので愛に参上
One, two, three, arriving in love!
君はひとりだ だから歌う
You're all alone, so I sing.
ひとりじゃない もういいでしょ
You're not alone, isn't that enough?
ソロプレイはおしまい だ、だ、だ、だってば
Solo play is over, because...
君が病めるときも 私そばにいるわ
Even when you are sick, I'll be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ そうよ
I'll always watch over you, yes.
怖くないのよ
You don't need to be afraid.
おねがい 君が欲しいの 慰めさせて
Please, I want you, let me comfort you.
shake shake 愛の才能で
Shake, shake, with the talent for love.
泣いてくれなきゃ 枯れてしまう
If you don't cry for me, I'll wither away.
濡れていたいね いいでしょ
I want to be wet, is that okay?
なめとって 飲みほしたい だ、だ、だ、だってば
I want to lick it up and drink it dry, because...
おねがい君が欲しいの 手探り散らして
Please, I want you, groping around.
shake shake ナッツのサイズで保存
Shake, shake, in the size of a nut.
わけてくれなきゃ 君じゃない
If you don't share it, you're not yourself.
感じてたいね いいでしょ
I want to feel it, is that okay?
吸いとって 救いたい だ、だ、だ、だってば
I want to suck it up and save you, because...
ねえ私知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
君がひとり涙流してるの知ってるよ
I know you're shedding tears all alone.
ぐすんぐすん凹んでた
Sniffling and feeling down...
弱い人からいいんじゃない
Isn't it fine to start with the weak ones?
朝が来るまで一緒越そう
Let's get through this together until morning.
もっと泣いたって何遍だって受けとめてあげる
No matter how much you cry, I'll accept it every time.
もう我慢しないでいっぱい吐きだしてね だ、だ、だ、だってば
Don't hold back anymore, let it all out, because...
おねだりしてみてほしいの ダーリン
I want you to pester me, Darling.
ダーリン あなた私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to what I say at all.
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
I've told you so much to stop smoking and drinking.
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず
Every day two packs and seven cans without fail.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても
Even if your liver is ruined and you kick the bucket,
看病してあげないんだから
I'm not going to nurse you!
ああ言やこう言う てこでもきかない
You have a comeback for every remark, and won't budge an inch.
あなたのハートは真っ黒です
Your heart is pitch black.
言いたいことは言わないし
You won't say what you want to say.
（行きたいとこからやりたいことまで決めてるくせにだんまりさん）
(Even though you've decided everything from where to go to what to do, Mr. Silence)
ねえ そんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない？保存
Hey, isn't that like an idiot?
そうじゃない？ じゃない？ じゃない？
Isn't that right? Right? Right?
（言いたいことあるならさっさと言えば？）
(If you have something to say, why not say it already?)
いつも思わせぶりな感じで
With your always-teasing vibe,
察してほしい感じで
and that vibe of wanting me to guess,
わざと口にしないの
you don't put it into words on purpose.
ずるくない？
Isn't that unfair?
（馬鹿じゃないの？）（わからないの？）
(Are you an idiot?) (Don't you get it?)
おねがいダーリン 見て聞いて
Please, Darling, look at me, listen.
欲しいのは形のないもの保存
What I want is a shapeless thing.
馬力にしないわ
I won't make fun of you.
見て聞いて 覗いてよ
Look, listen, peek in
瞳の奥の方
deep into my eyes.
真っ直ぐ見つめて
Gaze straight ahead,
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to pester me.
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all.
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに 今ではすっかり知らんぷり
I've gazed at you so gallantly, yet now you're completely playing dumb.
ていうか それって胡坐かいてるだけなんじゃないんですか
I mean, aren't you just resting on your laurels?
ぶっちゃけ 舌先三寸
To be frank, you're all talk.
あなたのお陰で私のハートはボロボロです
Thanks to you, my heart is in tatters.
つれない時はつれないし
When you're cold, you're cold,
（そっちがなかなか言い出さないからいつも私が舵取りじゃん）
(you won't readily speak, so I'm always the leader, yeah?)
ねえ なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない？
Hey, isn't that somewhat stupid?
そうじゃない？ じゃない？ じゃない？保存
Isn't that right? Right? Right?
（そんなことしてて楽しいの？）
(Do you have fun doing things like that?)
どこか足元見てる感じで
Feeling like you're watching my step,
ねあさされてる感じで
feeling like I'm being appraised,
（なにそれ）
(What's that?)
駆け引きやら勝ち負けじゃないんじゃない？
isn't this not about tactics and winning or losing?
（そういうめんどくさいことしてるからめんどくさいことになるんだよ）
(Because you do such annoying things, it turns into an annoying situation!)
寡黙なダーリン ねえ聞いて
Silent Darling, hey, listen.
切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Sadness isn't just for decoration.
よそ見しないで 逃げないで
Don't look away, don't run away.
触ってよ 心の奥の方
Touch deep into my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない
It's not just a momentary thing.
おねだりしてはくれないの？保存
Won't you pester me?
言葉に出来ない臆病さは保存
The cowardice you can't put into words
強さではないのよ
is not strength.
（ほんとそれな）
(So true!)
甘えてないで
Don't depend on me,
口に出してよ保存
say it out loud!
（もうちゃんとこっち向いてって言ってんだろ）保存
(I'm telling you to properly face me already!)
おねがいダーリン 見て聞いて
Please, darling, look at me and listen
欲しいのは形のないもの
What I want is a shapeless thing
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて
I won't make fun of you, look at me and listen
覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
Peek deep inside my eyes
寡黙なダーリン 寝てないで
Silent darling, don't sleep!
暴いてよ 私の素顔を
Expose my honest face
おねがいダーリン そばにいて
Please, darling, stay by my side
触らせて 心の奥の方
Let me touch deep in your heart
真っ直ぐ見つめて
Gaze straight ahead
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try pestering me
おねがいダーリン
Please, darling!
うわー！ぺこらさん！
Wow! Pekora-san!
きたよー！きたー！
I came! I'm here!
やっと二人で歌えてめっちゃ嬉しいです！
I'm so happy we finally got to sing together!
いや、まずはこれを言わせて、ビビ。
No, first let me say this, Bibi.
うん？
Yeah?
お誕生日おめぺこ！
Happy Birthday, Ome-peko!
やったー！おめぺこ！ありがとう！
Yay! Ome-peko! Thank you!
おめぺこ！
Ome-peko!
え、去年さ、ビビ凸待ちしたじゃないですか。
Hey, last year, I did a birthday call-in stream.
してたっけ？
Did you?
え、覚えてないんか！おい！
What, you don't remember?! Hey!
え、ぺこら行った？
Wait, did Pekora go?
来てくれたやん！
You came!
あ、行ったよね！行った、ぺこ、行ったよね！
Ah, I did! I went, peko, I went, right!
突然サプライズで、マネージャーさんから、ぺこらさんからのプレゼントを...
With a sudden surprise, through the manager, a present from Pekora-san...
あ、そう！あ、思い出した、思い出した！
Ah, yes! Ah, I remember, I remember!
思い出した？
You remember?
いや、おめでとう。今年はほら...
No, congratulations. This year, look...
おい、忘れてるじゃんか！
Hey, you forgot!
ビビ、ビビ、期待...
Bibi, Bibi, expect...
おい！ビビ、今日さ、そのプレゼント付けてきたのにさ、気づいてへんなって思ってさ。
Hey! Bibi wore that present today, and I thought, "She didn't notice..."
あ、いや、付けてたやん、付けてた、きつ...
Ah, no, you were wearing it, wearing it, tight...
ヘアクリップ付けてた、今日入り。
I wore the hair clip when I arrived today.
いや、わかってた、いや、付けてくれてたな、っていうふうに思ってたけど、ちょっと恥ずかしくて言えなかったな、みたいな。
No, I knew! I thought, "Oh, she's wearing it," but I was a bit embarrassed to say it.
嘘つけ！嘘つけ！
Liar! Liar!
いや、それぐらい嬉しかったんですよ。
No, but that's how happy I was.
だから去年に引き続き、今年もこうやってぺこら先輩におめでとうって言ってもらえて嬉しい！
So, continuing from last year, I'm so happy to have Pekora-senpai wish me happy birthday again this year!
ビビ大歓喜！
Bibi is overjoyed!
いや、ぺこらもね、ビビちゃんとさ、二人で歌うのってなかなかないぺこだからね。
Pekora is too, singing with Bibi-chan, just the two of us, doesn't happen often, peko.
見てる人も多分嬉しいぺこなんじゃないかなって思うよ。
I think the viewers are probably very happy, peko.
本当にペコビビ最強！最強！最強！
Seriously, Peko-Bibi is the strongest! Strongest! Strongest!
何が最強じゃ！ぺこマリ最強！
What do you mean strongest?! Peko-Mari is the strongest!
ぺこマリ最強！
Peko-Mari is the strongest!
うわ、来た！
Whoa, she came!
かかってこいや！
Come at me!
お前誰だよ！
Who even are you!
あ、お誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！
Ah, happy birthday! Thank you!
ビビ, 何歳になったの？
Bibi, how old did you turn?
いや、ビビは、ぴちぴちの22ちゃん！
Well, Bibi is a fresh 22-chan!
22ちゃん？あれ、去年まで何歳だったんだっけ？
22-chan? Wait, how old were you until last year?
22ちゃんです！
22-chan!
やかましいわ！何が22ちゃん、黙れよ！
Shut up! "22-chan" my foot, shut up!
みそじ...
Age 30...
みそじって言うな！お前も！
Don't say age 30! You too!
歳取らないで。
Don't age.
みそじにならない。鬼にならない。
I won't turn 30. I won't become a demon.
みそじ、やめて、やめて。
Age 30, stop it, stop it.
ならないよ。
I won't.
ならない？
You won't?
なったほうがいいけどね。ちゃんと間に入ってと。
It's better if you do, though. Let's get in between.
なんでよ！ペコビビの空間...
Why! Our Peko-Bibi space...
でもさ、マリンちゃんさ、そんなにずっとビビのなんか影響受けて、ぺこら先輩...
But Marine-chan, you've always been influenced by Bibi, Pekora-senpai...
ギャル、ギャルに影響...
Gal, influenced by gals...
お前陰キャなの？ギャルにしないで、勝手に。
Are you a loner? Don't make me a gal on your own.
マリンちゃんの影響受けたらどうなるんやっけ？
What happens if someone is influenced by Marine-chan?
エッチになる。
They become lewd.
なんでやねん！ホロライブ、これ以上エッチなメンバー増えたらあかんの。
Why?! Hololive shouldn't have any more lewd members.
てか、そんなこと言いながら、でも... ちょっと待って、この状況楽しんでるよね？
But saying that, still... Wait a minute, you're enjoying this situation, aren't you?
え？楽しくねえし！
Eh? I'm not enjoying it!
楽しそうだよ！
You look like you are!
なんかさ、ビビを挟むことによって、二人の新しいシナジーみたいな、なんかこの、何ていうの？
Like, by putting Bibi in the middle, you two have a new synergy, like, what do you call it...
あ、ネ、ネット...
Ah, ne, net...
7年... 7年やってるとちょっと倦怠期みたい...
7 years... Doing this for 7 years makes it feel like a weariness period...
え、でもぺこら、最近マリンのさ、好きなところ増えた。
But Pekora has grown to like more things about Marine lately.
え、ちょっと待って。はい、ちょっと待って。これビビの生誕祭なんですけど。
Wait, wait, hold on. This is Bibi's birthday celebration!
ビビの生誕祭なんですけど、どういうこと？何、急に。何ノロケですか？
This is Bibi's birthday celebration, so what is this? What's with this sudden flirting?
いや、なんか、やっぱさ、元からポテンシャルも高いし、マリンってもう、今さ、来ただけで空気変えてたやん、ペコビビの空気を。
No, I mean, she's always had high potential, and Marine just changed the atmosphere the moment she got here, the Peko-Bibi atmosphere.
確かに。
True.
そういうのもあるけど、7年目にして気づいたの。
There's that too, but I realized it in our 7th year.
7年目にして？
In your 7th year?
ぺこらは、マリンの暴言が好きなの。誰でもいいわけじゃないって。
Pekora likes Marine's verbal abuse. Not just anyone's.
え、誰でもいいわけじゃない？！
Not just anyone's?!
何それ！このウサギめ！このウサギめ！
What's that! This rabbit! This rabbit!
圧が足りない、そんな。そんな圧がない。このウサギめ、この...
Not enough pressure, like that. There's no pressure like that. This rabbit...
このウサギ！このみそじマリンちゃん！
This rabbit! This age-30 Marine-chan!
今日誕生日だからさ、誕生日...
It's her birthday today, so birthday...
便もさ、ビビちゃん、前からさ、MVP, MVPって言ってたやん。
But Bibi-chan, you've been saying "MVP, MVP" for a while, right?
そうだね。
Yeah.
だからさ、別にぺこマリでも、ペコビビでもなく、3人でMVPやればいいぺこじゃん！
So, it doesn't have to be Peko-Mari or Peko-Bibi, we can just do MVP as a trio, peko!
仲良くやろう、真ん中に、ほら真ん中に。
Let's get along, in the middle, look, in the middle.
うまいこと言うて。
Nicely said.
M V P!
意外とデカいな、お前。
You're surprisingly big.
確かに。
Indeed.
そうなんだよね。両手に花や！両手に花！
That's true. Flowers in both hands! Flowers in both hands!
お集まりー！ イェーイ！
Thanks for gathering! Yay!
ね、このMVさ、なんか一曲やらな？
Hey, since we're in this music video space, shouldn't we do a song?
いいじゃん！ やろうぜ、やろうぜ！
That sounds great! Let's do it! Let's do it!
なんか曲が流れてきた気するけど、でも嬉しい！やったー！
I feel like some music started playing, but I'm so happy! Yay!
歌っていいですか？ いいよ！
Can we sing? Sure!
やったー！ いこう！
Yay! Let's go!
「キスをあげるよ」
"I'll give you a kiss"
今 気付いた 想い
I just realized my love
どんな 言葉 でも 足りない
that is beyond words
から
because...
ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー！
One, two, three, four!
[楽曲：初恋サイダー]
[Song: Hatsukoi Cider]
当たり前すぎるぐらい
It's way too obvious
友達の時間が長かったせいで
since we've been longtime friends
あなたのクセや性格だって
all of your personality quirks,
他の子より知ってんの
I know them better than the other girls
はぁ〜 意気地なしで恥ずかしがり屋な
Ah, you're a shy coward
あなたをもう待ってられないの！
I can't wait for you anymore!
「キスをあげるよ」
「I'll give you a kiss」
今さら「好き」なんて言葉より
would send a clearer message than words like "I like you"
キキメあるでしょ？
Don't you think it'd work better?
あなたにだけはそっと教えてあげる
I want to gently tell only you
胸の奥小さいつぼみのぬくもり
the warmth of the little bud growing in my heart
時々甘えてみたり
Sometimes trying to depend on you
拗ねてみたりそんな作戦らしくない
or sulking, it's not like me to play such games
か弱きオトメじゃ勝てないの
A delicate maiden won't win your heart
この恋だけは負けらんない
I must not lose this love
はぁ〜 鈍感なあなたのこと
Ah, as I want an insensitive fellow like you
振り向かせたいから勝負かけるの！
to notice me, I'll take a gamble on you!
「キスをあげるよ」
「I'll give you a kiss」
「愛してます」なんて言葉より
would be more attractive than words like "I love you"
魅力的でしょ？
Don't you think it's more alluring?
聞こえちゃうぐらい速くなるドキドキ
My heartbeat goes faster than you could hear
初恋はサイダーみたいに弾ける
First love is sparkling like a cider
“友達同士”
"Just being friends"
そんな境界線
That kind of boundary line
今すぐに飛び越えたいの
I want to jump across it right away
「キスをあげるよ」
「I'll give you a kiss」
今さら「好き」なんて言葉より
would send a clearer message than words like "I like you"
キキメあるでしょ？
Don't you think it'd work better?
あなたにだけはそっと教えてあげる
I want to gently tell only you
胸の奥小さいつぼみのぬくもり
the warmth of the little bud growing in my heart
感じて
Feel it
せーのっ！
One, two...
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that's no good.
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
Look, it won't work.
心は進化するよ もっと もっと
Our hearts will keep on evolving, more and more.
[楽曲：恋愛サーキュレーション]
[Song: Renai Circulation]
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If words will ruin our relationship,
言葉を消せばいいやって
then we won't need them.
思ってた 恐れてた
Don't you think so? Are you scared?
だけどあれ？ なんか違うかも
But wait. Something's not right.
千里の道も一歩から
A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step.
石のようにかたいそんな意志で
So I'll go on with a resolution as firm as stone.
ちりも積もれば大和撫子？
If all the dust settles, I'll be a Yamato Nadeshiko!
「し」抜きで いや死ぬ気で！
I'm going to try my best with all I've got!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy and fluttering, fluttery and fluffy.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Fluttery and fluffy, fluffy and fluttering.
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
I can fly to the moon if you just call my name.
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy and fluttering, fluttery and fluffy.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Fluttery and fluffy, fluffy and fluttering.
あなたが
Just you...
笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
smiling is enough to make me smile too.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God...
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's just a prank of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
being able to meet you...
幸せなの
makes me so happy.
でも そんなんじゃ
But that's...
だめ
no good!
もう そんなんじゃ
Come on, that's...
ほら
look!
心は進化するよ
My heart is going to evolve...
もっと もっと
more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ
No, that's...
いやだ
not enough.
ねぇ そんなんじゃ
Hey, that's...
まだ
still not it!
私のこと見ててね
Keep looking at me...
ずっと ずっと
forever and ever!
私の中のあなたほど
As much as you are a part of me,
あなたの中の私の存在は
my presence inside of you...
まだまだ大きくないことも
is still not very big,
わかってるけれど
I know that, but...
今この同じ
Right now, this same...
瞬間
moment,
共有してる
sharing this...
実感
feeling.
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ
Even dust, when piled up, can create a mountain...
略して ちりつもやまとなでしこ！
Shortened to: Chiri-Tsumo Yamato Nadeshiko!
くらくらり
Dizzy, dizzy...
くらくらる
feeling dizzy...
あなたを見上げたら
When I look up at you,
それだけで眩しすぎて
just that is too dazzling.
くらくらる
Dizzy, dizzy...
くらくらり
feeling dizzy...
あなたを想っている
Just thinking of you...
それだけで溶けてしまう
makes me melt away.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God...
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's just a prank of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
being able to meet you...
幸せなの
makes me so happy.
こ・い・す・る
L-O-V-I-N-G
き・せ・つ・は
S-E-A-S-O-N is
よ・く・ば・り
G-R-E-E-D-Y
サーキュレーション
Circulation!
こ・い・す・る
L-O-V-I-N-G
き・も・ち・は
F-E-E-L-I-N-G is
よ・く・ば・り
G-R-E-E-D-Y
サーキュレーション
Circulation!
こ・い・す・る
L-O-V-I-N-G
ひ・と・み・は
E-Y-E-S are
よ・く・ば・り
G-R-E-E-D-Y
サーキュレーション
Circulation!
こ・い・す・る
L-O-V-I-N-G
お・と・め・は
M-A-I-D-E-N-S are
よ・く・ば・り
G-R-E-E-D-Y
サーキュレーション
Circulation!
ふわふわり
Fluffy, fluffy...
ふわふわる
floating lightly...
あなたが名前を呼ぶ
When you call my name,
それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
just that makes me float into space.
ふわふわる
Fluffy, fluffy...
ふわふわり
floating lightly...
あなたが笑っている
When you are smiling,
それだけで笑顔になる
just that makes me smile too.
神様ありがとう
Thank you, God...
運命のいたずらでも
even if it's just a prank of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
being able to meet you...
幸せなの
makes me so happy.
でも そんなんじゃ
But that's...
だめ
no good!
もう そんなんじゃ
Come on, that's......
ほら
look!
心は進化するよ
My heart is going to evolve...
もっと もっと
more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ
No, that's...
いやだ
not enough.
ねぇ そんなんじゃ
Hey, that's...
まだ
still not it!
私のこと見ててね
Keep looking at me...
ずっと ずっと
forever and ever!
chAngE なびかない 流されないよ
chAngE, I won't sway, I won't be swept away!
今感じることに 素直でいたいの
I want to stay true to what I'm feeling now.
chAngE 何度でも 生まれ変わるの
chAngE, no matter how many times, I will be reborn.
悲しみも抱きしめて 走り出すよ
Embracing my sadness, I'll start running.
タノシイ裏切りにあって
Faced with a pleasant betrayal,
とらわれない私がここにいるの
here I am, unbound.
足りない 尽きない なんだって
It's not enough, it never ends, whatever it is,
もっと 歪ませてよ
distort it even more!
パターン化したこんな世界じゃ
In a world that has become so patterned,
自分が誰なのか分からなくなる
I start to lose track of who I am.
枠にはまりたくないわ
I don't want to fit into a mold,
決めつけないでよ
so don't make assumptions about me.
なんでそんなためらって
Why do you hesitate so much...
満たされないあなたはどこにいるの？
and where are you who are not satisfied?
消えない 錆びない
It doesn't fade, it doesn't rust,
ふりきって もっとハウらせてよ
shake them off and make me howl more.
変わったから気づく世界は
The world I realize because I've changed
今の私を映してくれるでしょう
will project my current self, right?
あなたの思う未来は
In the future you think of,
何が映っているの？
what is projected?
愛なき明日へ行くの
I'll go to the loveless tomorrow.
引きとめないで 恋しくたって
Don't hold me back, even if I miss you,
私は進みたい
I want to go forth.
chAngE 止まらない 振り向かないよ
chAngE, I won't stop, I won't look back,
いつだって真実求めていたいの
I want to always be searching for the truth.
涙も
Even my tears...
愛おしく思える気がする
...I feel like I can hold them dear.
chAngE 忘れない 失くしたくない
chAngE, I won't forget, I don't want to lose it,
喜びも抱きしめて
so embracing even my happiness,
走り出すよ
I'll run!
あなたのもとから 離れてしまっても
Even if I stray away from you,
私は私らしく I wanna chAngE
the way I want me to, I wanna chAngE!
私が変わった先にあなたがいるなら
If I am changed and you are there...
あなたが変わった先に私がいるなら
...and if you are changed and I am there...
chAngE
Oh...
chAngE wo-oh
走り出すよ
I'll run!
chAngE なびかない 流されないよ
chAngE, I won't be bent, I won't be swept away,
今感じることにお互い素直でいたいの
I want us both to stay honest to how we feel now.
誰かの思い通りにはさせないわ
I won't let it go the way someone wants it to.
chAngE 何度でも生まれ変わるの
chAngE, I will be reborn, no matter how many times,
悲しみも抱きしめて
embracing even my sadness,
走り出すよ
I'll run!
ふたりで同じ景色が見れるなら
If I can see the same view with you,
あなたのもとにいつかは帰りたいわ
I want to go back to you someday.
私は私らしく I wanna chAngE
The way I want me to, I wanna chAngE!
あのね
Hey...
I say 私、大丈夫？
I say, "Am I okay?"
Maybe うまくやれるはず
Maybe, I should be able to do this well.
走りたい 息継ぎもしないまま
I want to run, without even taking a breath.
あっそう、終わりが来るのなら
Ah, I see. If the end is coming...
別に寂しくなんかない
it's not like I'm lonely or anything.
真実は心の奥の方
The truth is deep within my heart.
自分のことすら愛せないまま
Unable to even love myself,
君のこと守れるのかな
I wonder if I can protect you?
信じて
Believe in me.
どうか、正真正銘のこの思いを聴いて
Please, listen to these genuine feelings of mine,
私、全身全霊で歌うから
because I will sing with all my heart and soul.
大丈夫、世界はこんなに綺麗だと
It's okay, I know the world is this beautiful...
分かってる、分かってる、分かってる、分かってるよ！
...I know, I know, I know, I know!
ごめんね、じれったい
I'm sorry for being so frustrating.
足りない、こんなんじゃ誰も愛せないの
It's not enough, like this I can't love anyone.
止めない、止まることは知らないの
I won't stop, I don't know how to stop!
言葉足らず、失くしてしまう物ばかりだ
With my clumsy words, I only end up losing things.
Luna say maybe...
降るのは
What is falling...
maybe, rainy
愛せ、どんな自分でも
Love yourself, no matter who you are,
Navy色に染まるまで
until you're dyed in navy blue.
時間はかかるかもしれないけど
It might take some time, but...
I know, 輝くしかないこと
I know, there's nothing to do but shine,
ハイライト、塗り続けるしかない
and keep painting the highlight.
真実はちゃんと言わなくちゃね
I have to say the truth properly,
目に見えるものが
so that what can be seen...
続くと、ずっと
will continue, forever.
そう、ずっと
Yes, forever.
想いたい
I want to believe...
君に、半信半疑な素振りして
showing you a half-doubting attitude,
心、空回り、遠回り
my heart spinning its wheels, taking the long way around.
最低だ、もう一回やり直せるのなら
I'm the worst; if I could start over once more,
素直になりたい、なりたい、なりたいと願ったジレンマ
I want to be honest, I want to, I want to... that's my dilemma.
このまま、1人じゃ何もできない
Just like this, I can't do anything alone.
...るのは自分次第
...is up to myself.
初めて背中を見たときに
When I saw your back for the first time,
覚悟決めた
I made up my mind.
どこまで行けるのか
How far can I go?
届くのか
Will my voice reach?
わからないよ
I just don't know,
臆病がそこに立っている
cowardice is standing right there.
3秒前バックステージ
Three seconds before backstage,
震える背中を君にあずけて
leaving my trembling back to you.
この運命的出会いは
This fateful encounter is something
信じた
I believe in.
そうきっと 偶然みたいな
Yes, surely like a coincidence,
たぶん神様のいたずらです
it's probably a trick of God's.
どうか
Please let
正真正銘のこの想いが
this genuine feeling
君のところにちゃんと届くまで
reach you safely.
ここで私ステージの上で歌うから
Because I'll sing right here on this stage,
待ってる 待ってる
I'm waiting, waiting.
だからこの場所大切にしたいの
That's why I want to cherish this place.
これが正真正銘の私だから
Because this is the genuine me.
大丈夫 もう怖くはないわ
It's alright, I'm not afraid anymore.
たまにつまずくことならあるけれど
Though I might stumble sometimes,
一番特等席で君の笑顔見たいんだ
I want to see your smile from the best seat.
私だけの特権
It's my exclusive privilege.
見えない未来 手探り今日も
Groping through an unseen future today too,
ステージの上で証明してみせるから
I will prove myself on this stage.
ここにしかないストーリー
A story that only exists here.
君にまだ話せてないことばかりあるんだ
There are still so many things I haven't told you yet.
聞いてほしいの あのね...
I want you to listen, you see...
みんなー！
Everyone!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
皆さん、楽しんでくれてますかー？
Are you all having fun?
ずっとね、コメントもたくさん見えてます。みんな盛り上げてくれてありがとう！
I've been seeing so many comments. Thank you all for hyping it up!
はい、ということでですね、ライブも終盤になっているんですけれども、なんか先ほどスタッフさんにですね、トレンド1位だとお聞きしました！
Alright, the live show is nearing its end, but I just heard from the staff that we're trending at number one!
え、まだトレンド1位？
Wait, we're still trending at number one?
ビビ生誕祭2024、みんなポストしてくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for posting using #BibiBirthFestival2024!
そして、とんでもないことに一瞬「いやらしい」もトレンド入りしたみたいです。
And incredibly, it seems 'iyarashii' also trended for a moment!
トレンド入りするなかい！
Why on earth is that trending?!
ビビ今年ラッキーキーを流行らせていきたいって言ってたのに、ラッキーキーよりいやらしいの方が流行ってしまっとるがな、はい。
Even though I said I wanted to make 'Lucky Key' trend this year, 'iyarashii' ended up trending more than 'Lucky Key'!
いや、でも皆さんのおかげで本当にありがとうございます！
But seriously, it's all thanks to everyone, so thank you so much!
はい、次がですね、最後の曲になるんですが、
Yes, the next one is the final song,
なんと、ビビの初めてのオリジナル楽曲を披露したいと思います！
and I will be performing Bibi's very first original song!
やったー！やっと皆さんにお届けできます。
Yay! I can finally present it to you all.
タイトルは「ビビッドキュート」です！
The title is 'Vivid Cute'!
ということで、この後披露させていただきます！
So, I'll be performing it right after this!
じゃ、一旦ちょっと準備してくるね。お水飲んでくるわ。待ってて！
Let me go prepare for a bit. I'll get some water. Wait for me!
鮮やか変身メイクアップ
A vivid transformation makeup!
ビビッドキュート
Vivid Cute
超ヴィヴィっとくるっしょ？
It strikes a chord, doesn't it?
ビビッドキュート
Vivid Cute
アップデート順調！
Updates are running smoothly!
超ヴィヴィっとくるっしょ？
It strikes a chord, doesn't it?
ビビッドキュート
Vivid Cute
アップデート順調！
Updates are running smoothly!
なりたい自分 変幻自在
The self I want to be is ever-changing.
悩まないショッピング 直感でポチっと！
Worry-free shopping, clicking on instinct!
案外単純なことで
Over surprisingly simple things,
気分も未来もアガるの
both my mood and future soar.
世界平和に比べりゃ私の前髪とか
Compared to world peace, things like my bangs
微々たるもんだけど こっちのが大事！
are trivial, but they're way more important!
「好きな自分」は 好きに自分でつくるの
My favorite self is made by myself, however I like,
カラフルデコレーションショー
so let's colorful-decorate the show.
ねえ、かわいい？
Hey, am I cute?
憧れ真似して 自分色へ
Imitating my idols to find my own colors.
鏡の前でセルフィー 街中どこだってランウェイ
Selfies in front of the mirror, making every street my runway.
ビビッドにキュートに変身メ
Vividly, cutely, making transformation...
変身メイクアップ
Transformation Makeup!
トレンドしたい！
I want to trend!
セール狙って爆買い
Scouting out sales and buying in bulk!
トレンドしない？
Wanna trend?
逆張り少し後悔
Slightly regretting going against the grain.
トレンドしたい
I want to trend,
けど しっくりくる自分がいい
but I'd rather just feel like myself.
あっちこっちのリアル
Real life here, there, and everywhere!
差し色ひとつでも
Even with just an accent color,
こんなに変わるのに
it changes so much.
何もしないなんてのは もったいない
Doing nothing at all is such a waste.
思いつくまま
Just follow your whims
試すのです
and give it a try!
目の覚めるようなビフォーアフターじゃなくてもി
Even if it's not an eye-opening before-and-after,
君が気づいてくれたら大成功
if you notice it, it's a huge success!
1秒前の自分の決心を褒めましょう
Let's praise our own decision from just a second ago!
ビビッドに色付くの 毎日が
My everyday life becomes vividly colored,
キュートな音色も聞こえてきて
and I can hear cute melodies too.
魔法少女のようなシチュエーション
A situation just like a magical girl's.
「好き」の気持ちで何にでもなれるの
With feelings of "love," you can become anything!
カラフルデコレーションショー (ねえかわいい？)
Colorful Decoration Show (Hey, am I cute?)
憧れ真似して自分色へ
Imitating what I admire to find my own colors.
鏡の前でセルフィー 街中どこだってランウェイ
A selfie in front of the mirror, making the whole city my runway!
ビビッドにキュートに (変身メイクアップ)
Vividly, cutely (Transformation makeup!)
ピンクのリップでスキップ
Skipping with pink lips,
街も色づいていく
and the town is getting colored too.
ピンクのリップでスキップ
Skipping with pink lips,
なりたい自分へと もっともっとメイクアップ
Making up more and more to become the self I want to be.
ビビッドキュート
Vivid Cute!
超ヴィヴィっとくるっしょ？
It hits you super vividly, right?
ビビッドキュート
Vivid Cute!
アップデート順調！
Update going smoothly!
ビビッドキュート
Vivid Cute!
超ヴィヴィっとくるっしょ？
It hits you super vividly, right?
ビビッドキュート
Vivid Cute!
アップデート順調！
Update going smoothly!
きつすぎる。ちょっと、
That was too exhausting. Let me...
お水飲んできます。
go drink some water.
ひゃっこ。ただいま！
Cold! I'm back!
みんな、ビビの初めてのオリジナルソロ曲
Everyone, Vivi's very first original solo song...
「ビビッドキュート」、聴いていただきました！
...'Vivid Cute', you just heard it!
どうやった？
How was it?
ん？
Hmm?
良かった？可愛い？
Was it good? Was I cute?
知ってる！
I know!
やったー！
Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ということで、ちょっと新曲について詳しくご紹介したいなと思います！
With that, I'd like to introduce the new song in a bit more detail!
改めてタイトルは「ビビッドキュート」です！
Once again, the title is "Vivid Cute"!
じゃーん！
Tada!
うわー！何だこの美少女？
Wow! Who is this beautiful girl?
あ、ビビやった。可愛すぎて一瞬誰かわからんかった。
Ah, it's Vivi. I was too cute, I couldn't tell who it was for a second.
はい。まあ、いつも可愛いですけどね。
Yes. Well, I'm always cute, though.
はい、え、こちらですね。
Yes, so here it is.
え、可愛い女の子がコスメで変身するような可愛い気持ちを
It's a song filled with the cute feeling of a cute girl transforming with cosmetics...
歌にした楽曲になっております。
...turned into a song.
はい。まあ、ビビといえばメイク担当ですから。
Yes, well, since Vivi is in charge of makeup,
あのときのワクワク感をね、思い出しながら歌っています。
I sang this while remembering that feeling of excitement.
え、ミュージックビデオも作成中なので、また告知するから待っててね！
The music video is also in progress, so I'll announce it soon. Please look forward to it!
そして、音源リリースは本日24時からになります！
And the song release will be today starting from 24:00!
みんなたくさん聴いてね！
Everyone, please listen to it a lot!
はい、そして、皆さんお待ちかね！
Yes, and next, what you've all been waiting for!
綺々羅々ヴィヴィ誕生日記念2026グッズが発売されます！
Kikirara Vivi Birthday Celebration 2026 goods are going on sale!
はい、可愛い！
Ah, so cute!
ちょっと、じゃあ早速ひとつひとつ見ていきましょう！
So, let's take a look at each item right away!
ひとつめはこちら！
First one is this!
「ヴィヴィとおやすみ抱き枕カバー」
"Good Night with Vivi Body Pillow Cover"
え、なんか、え、これこそ「いやらしい」
Wait, somehow... wait, this is definitely "lewd"!
いやらしいですよね、これ。
This is pretty lewd, isn't it?
ヴィヴィ初の抱き枕カバーです！
This is Vivi's first body pillow cover!
イラストはnoncoママに描いていただきました！
The illustration was drawn by nonco-mama!
気分に合わせて表裏で使ってください。
Please use the front or back depending on your mood.
ふたつめはこちら！
The second one is this!
「ヴィヴィのめちゃかわ缶バッジ」
"Vivi's Super Cute Can Badge"!
今回のnoncoママのイラストを使った缶バッジです。
This can badge uses the illustration by nonco-mama.
え、なんか、ねえヴィヴィってこんな表情もできるんや、可愛い。
Wow, like, Vivi can actually make expressions like this too. So cute!
いろんなところにつけて、ヴィヴィをアピールしちゃってください。
Please attach it in various places and show off your love for Vivi!
ぜひ痛バッグも作ってね！
Be sure to make an ita-bag too!
みっつめはこちら！
The third one is this!
「ちびヴィヴィぬいぐるみキーホルダー」
"Chibi Vivi Plushie Keyholder"!
はい、このね、ちびヴィヴィ、ついに、ついにグッズ化となりました！
Yes, this Chibi Vivi has finally, finally been made into merch!
猫着ぐるみを着た、ちびヴィヴィになってます。
It features Chibi Vivi wearing a cat onesie.
いろんなところにつけて、たくさん可愛がってくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you attach it in various places and love it a lot.
ヴィヴィの他のキーホルダーとかと並べてつけても絶対可愛い。絶対可愛いです！
It'll definitely look cute if you attach it alongside other Vivi keyholders too!
よっつめはこちら！
The fourth one is this!
「ヴィヴィとおそろい推し活バッグ」
"Matching Vivi Oshi-katsu Bag"!
ヴィヴィがいつも持ってるバッグをイメージした推し活バッグです。
This is an oshi-katsu bag modeled after the bag Vivi always carries.
こちらぬいぐるみを入れて、街歩いてください！
Put your plushie inside and walk around town!
はぁ、可愛い。ヴィヴィとお揃いよ。
Ah, so cute. It matches with Vivi!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the full-set purchase bonus!
チェキ風ブロマイドカード！
A Cheki-style bromide card!
こちらはですね、ヴィヴィの直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージが入ってます。
This has Vivi's handwritten signature and a foil-stamped message!
メッセージの内容は届いてからのお・た・の・し・み！
As for the message, look forward to finding out when it arrives!
さらに、特典ボイスも付きます。
Plus, it comes with a bonus voice track!
タイトルは、「ベッドで一緒にゴロゴロしよう」です！
The title is: "Let's roll around in bed together"!
ヴィヴィと二人でベッドで一緒にゴロゴロしている気持ちになれるシチュエーションボイスになってます。
It's a situation voice track that makes you feel like you're rolling around in bed with Vivi.
みんな、これは絶対聞かないと！
Everyone, you absolutely have to listen to this!
さあ、ここまで、新曲告知とグッズ紹介でした！
Well, that's it for the new song announcement and merch showcase!
この後は、メン限もあるから、みんな、絶対絶対遊びに来てね！
After this, there's a members-only stream, so everyone, definitely come by!
何をやるかはまだお楽しみに！
Look forward to what we'll do!
ぜひ、まだの方はチャンネル登録と通知をオンにして
If you haven't yet, please subscribe and turn on notifications,
メン限の方にも入っていただき、アンコールも一緒に楽しめればと思います！
and join the members-only stream so we can enjoy the encore together!
ということで、ここまでお知らせをさせていただいたんですけれども、
And with that, I've shared all the announcements, but...
こうして、えー、初めてのね、生誕3Dライブを迎えることができたのも、
being able to welcome my very first birthday 3D live like this...
本当に、いつも応援してくださっている皆さんのおかげです！
is truly thanks to all of you who always support me!
日々、ヴィヴィが活動できているのは、ヴィヴィっ子の支えがあるからです。
The reason Vivi can keep active day by day is because of the support from my Vivids.
え、そして、改めてですね、この生誕祭、もう準備期間、結構ちょっと長かったんですけど、
Also, the preparation period for this birthday festival was quite long,
そんな中、ずっと支えてくださって、協力してくれた、尽力してくださったスタッフの皆さんも本当にありがとうございます！
but to all the staff members who supported and helped me along the way, thank you so much!
こうやって、たくさん支えてくださるスタッフの皆さんと、そして、ゲストで出てくださった、
With the staff who supported me so much, and the guests who appeared...
え、出てくださった、出てくださった、ホロメンの皆さんや、いつも仲良くしてくださってるホロメンの皆さんや、
the Hololive members who joined, and the ones who are always friendly with me,
そして、こうして今配信を見てくださっているそこのあなた！
and you right there, who are watching this stream right now!
の存在が、今のヴィヴィの背中を押してくださってます。
Your presence is what pushes Vivi forward.
本当にいつもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much, always!
なんか、ちょっと言葉で伝えるのは下手くそなんですが、
I'm not very good at putting it into words, but...
みんなの応援があるから、ヴィヴィはこれからも、どんどん、どんどん階段を上っていきたいと思います！
because of everyone's support, Vivi wants to keep climbing higher and higher!
みんな、ずっとずっと、ついてきてや！
Everyone, keep following me forever and ever!
それでは、メン限でお会いしましょう！
Well then, let's meet in the members-only stream!
せーの！
Ready, set...
うーーヴィヴィっ！またね！
Vivi! See you later!
大好きなvividへ
緊張で震える膝
To my beloved Vivids,
My knees were trembling from nervousness,
支えてくれてありがとう♡
みんながヴィヴィを
thank you so much for supporting me. ♡
You all made Vivi...
アイドルにしてくれたよ！
どんな困難でもみんながいれば
...into an idol!
No matter the difficulty, as long as I have everyone,
乗り越えていける！
これからも
I can overcome it!
From now on too...
ずっとそばにいて♡
...please stay by my side forever. ♡